A single shot can end the war.
Flags of Our Fathers is a war, drama, history film directed by Clint Eastwood.
There were five Marines and one Navy Corpsman photographed raising the U.S.
flag on Mt.
Suribachi by Joe Rosenthal on February 23, 1945.
This is the story of three of the six surviving
servicemen - John 'Doc' Bradley, Pvt.
Rene Gagnon and Pvt.
Ira Hayes - who fought in the battle to take Iwo Jima from the Japanese.
John 'Doc' Bradley, played by Ryan Phillippe.
Rene Gagnon, played by Jesse Bradford.
Ira Hayes, played by Adam Beach.
Keyes Beech, played by John Benjamin Hickey.
Bud Gerber, played by John Slattery.
Mike Strank, played by Barry Pepper.
Flags of Our Fathers is a 2006 American war drama film directed, co-produced,
and scored by Clint Eastwood and written by William Broyles Jr.
and Paul Haggis.
It is based on the 2000 book of the same name written by James Bradley and Ron Powers about the 1945 Battle of Iwo Jima, the five Marines
and one Navy corpsman who were involved in raising the flag on Iwo Jima, and the after effects of that event on their lives.
Taken from the American viewpoint of the Battle of Iwo Jima, the film is a companion piece to Eastwood's Letters from Iwo
Jima, which depicts the same battle from the Japanese viewpoint; the two films were shot back to back.
The film was released on October 20, 2006 by Paramount Pictures in
the United States and the Bahamas and by Warner Bros.
Pictures in international markets.
Although it was a box office failure, only grossing $65.9 million against a $90
million budget, the film received favorable reviews from critics.
The companion film Letters from Iwo Jima was released in Japan on December 9, 2006, and in the United States on December
20, 2006, grossing slightly more than Flags of Our Fathers and was deemed the superior film by critics.
The film explores themes of dying and death, japan,
world war ii, based on true story, pacific.
The tone is emotional.